Gottlieb, Delia Collection of Publications 6286 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Delia Gottlieb Collection of Publications
1939-2000
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gottlieb, Delia
6286 PUBS
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Publications.
9221409
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, July 14, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 26, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
9221409
- Miscellaneous Pamphlets, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: A Center of Achievement 1854-1954, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Combined Campaign
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: In Just Two Years: Iowa Tests of Basic Skills, Grades 3-9, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: The City Club of New York, Distinguished New Yorker Award Dinner to Jacob S. Potofsky., 1969; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Arthur Goldberg
    Notes: October 28, 1969.
  - Item 4: Bad News Makes Good Headlines, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Bad News Makes Good Headlines, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Copy 2.
- Ten Years of Progress: A Report on Israel Harrison and Potofsky 1958, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Ten year of progress: a report on Israel, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Jacob S. Potofsky; George M. Harrison
- New York Hotel Trades Council Pension Plan (2 copies) 1952, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Pension Plan, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: New York Hotel Trades Council and Hotel Association of New York City
  - Item 2: Pension Plan, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
- NMU Pension Plan, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: NMU Pension Plan, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: National Maritime Union (NMU)
  - Item 2: NMU Pension Plan, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: NMU Pension and Welfare Plan. 2 year report, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: January 1, 1951 - December 31, 1952
  - Item 4: Plan NMU de seguridad de empleo, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Language: Spanish.
- Ironworkers Welfare Plan, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Ironworkers welfare plan of Western Pennsylvania. 1st Annual Report, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Iron Workers: 1st Annual report, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Iron Workers: 1st Annual report, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Painting Sandusky, Insurance and Pension Fund 1954-1958, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: 8th Annual Report. Painting Industry Insurance and Pension Fund, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: May 1, 1954.
  - Item 2: 9th Annual Report. Painting Industry Insurance and Pension Fund, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: May 1, 1955.
  - Item 3: 10th Annual Report. Painting Industry Insurance and Pension Fund, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: May 1, 1956. Ten Years of Progress, 1946-1956
  - Item 4: 11th Annual Report. Painting Industry Insurance and Pension Fund, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: May 1, 1957.
  - Item 5: 12th Annual Report. Painting Industry Insurance and Pension Fund, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: May 1, 1958.
  - Item 6: 12th Annual Report. Painting Industry Insurance and Pension Fund, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Elden La Mar. The Picture That Came to Life 1 Soft Cover Copy 1 Hard Cover Copy 1951, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: The Picture that came to life: the story of the Sidney Hillman Medical Center of the Male Apparel Industry of Philadelphia, and of the union which it serves, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Elden La Mar
    Notes: Softcover
  - Item 2: The Picture that came to life: the story of the Sidney Hillman Medical Center of the Male Apparel Industry of Philadelphia, and of the union which it serves, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: Hardcover
- ALWA. Security: The Central Issue Gosslieb and Schaap (2 copies), 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Security: the Central Issue, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: William P. Gottlieb; Walter E. Schaap
    Notes: The Health and Welfare Program of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers
  - Item 2: Security: the Central Issue, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Notes: The Health and Welfare Program of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers. Copy 2.
- Bonnie Tells Her Story As A Seeing Eye Dog (2 copies) 1963, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Bonnie Tells Her Story as a Seeing Eye Dog, 1963; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Notes: Comics book
  - Item 2: Bonnie Tells Her Story as a Seeing Eye Dog, 1963; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Notes: Comics book. Copy 2.
- Sidney Hillman Foundation: A Record of Service to the Community Welfare Program of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America Hardcover Together in Slipcase 1954, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Sidney Hillman Foundation: a record of service to the community, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Notes: Hardcover. In slipcase with "The Welfare Program: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America"
  - Item 2: The Welfare Program: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: William P. Gottlieb
    Notes: Hardcover. In slipcase with "Sidney Hillman Foundation: a record of service to the community"
- Sidney Hillman Foundation: A Record of Service to the Community (2 copies) 1954, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Sidney Hillman Foundation: a record of service to the community, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 2: Sidney Hillman Foundation: a record of service to the community, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Notes: Softcover. Copy 2.
- William Gottlieb The Welfare Program of the ACWA soft cover 1954, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: The Welfare Program: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
- William Gottlieb. This is the NMU 2 copies, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: This is the NMU: a picture history of the National Maritime Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 2: This is the NMU: a picture history of the National Maritime Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
- William Gottlieb. This is the NMU Hardcover in Embossed Slipcase, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: This is the NMU: a picture history of the National Maritime Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: Hardcover. In slipcase embossed "William P. Gottlieb"
- Miscellaneous William P. Gottlieb Company FilmStrip Pamphlets, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: BYPWB: Boost Your Profits With Beer, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Notes: Text to accompany a filmstrip.
  - Item 2: BYPWB: Boost Your Profits With Beer, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Notes: Text to accompany a filmstrip. Copy 2
  - Item 3: Within these walls: The Union House of Living Judaism, Berg Memorial, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Notes: Advertising for a filmstrip
  - Item 4: Americas New Dimensions: A Twentieth Century Fund Filmstrip Series, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Notes: Advertising for filmstrips
  - Item 5: Dollars for health, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 6: The Formation of Ferromagnetic Domains, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: H. J. Williams
    Notes: Text to accompany a filmstrip
  - Item 7: Teachers Guide. Around the World with Hebrew, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: Samuel Grand
  - Item 8: History in everyday things: the story of cups through the centuries, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 9: Okay, Greeley, We're Going West, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Notes: Advertising
  - Item 10: Satisfy Your Customers' Secret Needs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 11: Heath Science Series Filmstrips for Grades 7 and 8, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 12: Hold On, Miss Secretary, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 13: Let Your Students become Part of the Modern World of Social Studies Through the Magic of Educational Filmstrips, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Notes: Advertisement for filmstrips
  - Item 14: Let Your Students become Part of the Modern World of Social Studies Through the Magic of Educational Filmstrips, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Notes: Advertisement for filmstrips. Copy 2
  - Item 15: Heath Science Series Filmstrips for Grades 1-6, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Steven Fraser. Labor Will Rule Jacket and Clippings Only: Cataloged to Kheel Rare Books, 1991; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Labor Will Rule: Sidney Hillman and the Rise of American Labor, 1991; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Author: Steven Fraser
    Notes: Dust Jacket and news clippings only. Book cataloged to Kheel Rare Books: HD8073.H5 F84 Rare
- Gus Tyler, The Labor Revolution Jacket Only: Cataloged to Kheel Rare Books, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: The Labor Revolution; trade unions in a new America., 1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Gus Tyler
    Notes: Dust Jacket only. Book cataloged to Kheel Rare Books: HD6508 .T92 Rare
- Dorothy Goldberg. A Private View of a Public Life Jacket Only: Cataloged to Kheel Rare Books, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: A Private View of a Public Life, 1975; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Author: Dorothy Goldberg
    Notes: Dust Jacket only. Book cataloged to Kheel Rare Books: E840.8.G61 A34 Rare
- Esther Peterson. Restless Photographs and Clippings Only: Cataloged to Kheel Rare Books, 1991-1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Restless: the memoirs of labor and consumer activist Esther Peterson, 1995; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: Esther Peterson; Winifred Conkling
    Notes: Pictures and news clippings only. Cataloged to Kheel Rare Books: HC79.C63 P48 1995 Rare
- David Morse Mission of Justice and Peace. Jacket Only: Cataloged to Kheel Rare Books, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Mission of Justice and Peace; the visit of Pope Paul VI to the International Labour Conference, Geneva, Switzerland, 10 June 1969., Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Author: Rene Mossu; David Morse
    Notes: Dust Jacket only. Book cataloged to Kheel Rare Books: HD7801 .M53 Rare
- Rosalind Bryan Chaikin. "To My Memory Sing" Jacket only (2 copies): Cataloged to Kheel Rare Books, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: To My Memory Sing: a memoir based on letters amd poems from Sol Chick Chaikin, an American soldier in China-Burma-India during World War II, 1997; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Author: Rosalind Bryon Chaikin
    Notes: Dust Jacket only (2 copies). Book cataloged to Kheel Rare Books: CT275.C44 C43 1997 Rare